Most people think the
secret to making a
video that's gonna grow
a channel and a
business is good information,
good presenting, and like
a fancy setup and
studio. Now that stuff
kind of helps, but
that is not it
at all. The secret
is actually that you
need to get your
videos to become the
perfect gift. So to
explain, I want you
to play a game
with me called open
or pass. All you
do is you say
open or pass when
you see the thing
that I show you.
Pretty self -explanatory. Okay,
so here is the
first open or pass
challenge. Would you like
to open this gift?
Now, some of you
are gonna be like,
yes, that looks flipping
amazing. Others are probably
thinking, no, that is
way too flashy for
me. I don't want
that thing. And this
is exactly what happens
on YouTube. When your
dream viewers see your
video's wrapping paper, the
thumbnail and title, and
that's why this really
ugly thumbnail got 1
.2 million views, and
this polished one got
millions of views too,
because your video's packaging
is not about being
ugly or pretty at
all. It's about what
your viewer type is
drawn to. So all
we need to do
to get a click
is to work out
what their favorite wrapping
paper is, and then
we just keep giving
them that over and
over again so we
can scare off the
wrong people and only
get the right. That
means your goal is
to use the fail
as fast as you
can system to test
different wrapping paper styles
on your videos to
see what gets opened,
and then you just
repeat what works. And
if we have a
quick look here, I'll
scroll to the bottom
of my channel and
look. You can see
that's exactly what I'm
doing. The fail as
fast as you can
system where my thumbnails
keep changing and I'm
trying tons of different
things. And then, oh
look, something works. And
now all my thumbnails
look really similar because
that is what is
growing the channel and
the business. So I'm
not going to stop
doing that. That would
be absolutely insane until
it stops working. And
then I have to
repeat this whole system
again to find the
new thing that works.
And look how boring
they are compared to
my old channel film
booth. My viewers wanted
this. So that is
the secret to packaging.
We've got to make
what your ideal buyers
actually want to click
on. Now, I'm going
to pretend you said
you want to open
the wrapping. So we've
opened it and inside
is this. A Louis
Vuitton box. And I'm
going to ask you
the same question. Do
you want to open
this or do you
want to pass and
hope for something better?
All right. Now, some
of you, they're going
to be going, wow,
Louis Vuitton. Yes, please.
And others are going
to be thinking this
is tacky crap and
you have no interest
in it at all.
Now, this box here,
this represents your video's
format. So a format
is the structure that
encases your information, aka
the gift inside. And
there are loads of
different types of video
formats. So we have
deep dive, listicle, viewer
roast, rants, challenges, interviews,
stories, process, walkthrough, new,
news, news. And what
you need to understand
is like thumbnails and
titles, different viewer types
prefer different formats. And
if you build your
channel around a couple
of them that do
really well, and then
you try out a
new one that your
viewership wasn't growing on
and doesn't really want
from you, it's very
likely that video will
flop because it's not
how viewers like their
information boxed. So for
example, Alex Hormozy, if
you look at his
formats, he figured out
his viewers love long,
really deep dive kind
of videos. He just
repeats these like hour
long beasts. Now this
channel is in the
watch niche. He gets
tons of views just
talking about the latest
news. And he uses
the same format, same
thumbnail every time. And
it works. Then we
have my mate Finzar.
So he did this
challenge video that blew
up. So he repeated
that format. Look, same
thumbnail, same title, same
style of video style.
All of them performed
amazingly. And then we
have Whizzle Liz. Her
thing that she just
repeats over and again
is like these tough
love rants that are
very heavily story -based.
And our audience can't
get enough of them.
So just like with
thumbnails, what you are
going to do over
time is test different
formats on your channel
to see what works
and we do more
of it. But I'll
go deeper on that
in another video. But
also let me show
you this. So these
are my, my three
top performing videos in
their first 48 hours
of existence. Look at
that. Same title structure,
same thumbnail layout, same
format. These videos, when
you watch them, do
the same thing, but
with just different words.
And I'm going to
teach you how to
produce every single one
of these formats in
the writing module. So
now let's play the
final round of open
or pass. So now
I'm going to say
that you opened the
box. So let's have
a look inside. All
right. Look if it's
on. I think this
is going to be,
expect what?
It's a tea bag.
Are you kidding me?
Now in YouTube turns,
that final step is
where most people lose
their viewers because they
promised them fancy wrapping
in a Louis Vuitton
box and they give
them a tea bag.
And what that really
means is they don't
match or exceed their
viewers expectations inside the
actual video itself. So
if you want to
grow a channel, you
have to nail the
information delivery so that
it matches the viewers
expectations after the video.
So, of the click.
And it needs to
be the perfect payoff
for the thumbnail and
title as well. But
I am not going
to teach you just
to match a viewer's
expectation. Oh no, because
let me ask you
a question. What gift
do you prefer? The
one that you asked
for or the one
that you open from
your partner and it
was something you wanted
since you were a
child that you were
just so gobsmacked, they
got you. You tell
them I'm giving you
the good loving tonight.
That is what we
want our videos to
do. Good channels, match
expectations. expectations the next
level channels that could
sell sand to a
camel exceed them and
i mean just think
about the last youtube
video you absolutely loved
you came away from
it feeling like oh
that was way better
than i thought it
was going to be
right and that is
the secret to this
all and the cool
part about this is
when you get my
system working when you
know what wrapping paper
they want when you
know what format and
box they want and
then when you know
exactly how to deliver
on that and you
see it works you
just reuse everything you
use the same thumbnail
format the same title
with just a subtle
tweak use the same
intro the same video
structure sometimes i've literally
taken an intro off
a video and just
put it on a
new one because it
worked and this is
when ideating a video
goes from three hours
to 20 minutes and
writing a script goes
from days to hours
if you honestly want
to get more views
and sales and save
time then all you
do is just give
your viewers the gift
they want over and
over again so many
people ignore this because
it feels like we're
not doing it right
and it's not right
and it's not we
always have to reinvent
the wheel but viewers
who come to you
for louis vuitton they
don't go i'm getting
bored of being given
the world's most expensive
brand can i have
some uniclo please that
would be mental if
you don't do what
i've just told you
the system doesn't work
so now you know
what makes the perfect
video let's move on
to the next one
we're going to look
at everyone's least favorite
part of youtube thumbnails